Now that you've had that practice with EFIS, in this video,
你已经完成了关于 IIFE 的练习
we're going to take a look at the webpack fixes for our JavaScript problems.
现在来看一下 webpack 如何修复我们的 JavaScript 问题
So if we take a look at this code,
在这段代码中
you can see that I have the webpack config exactly as we ended it in the last lesson.
可以看到已经包含了上节课最后的 webpack 设置
So we have our styles loaders and everything.
包含了样式加载器等设置
But I've added this new section called output.
不过这里还添加了一个新的 output 部分
Up until now, we've used the default settings for output.
目前为止 我们都在使用默认的输出 (output) 设置
But to make our JavaScript work,
但是为了使 JavaScript 正常运行
I've added the library and libraryTarget settings.
我添加了这个 library 和 libraryTarget 设置
You don't have to worry too much about what those are doing,
不用太纠结这些设置的原理
but know that our JavaScript files,
你需要知道的是 JavaScript 文件中
our custom JavaScript is now going to be put
自定义的 JavaScript 会被放入我们自己的库 Client 中
The name client isn't important.
Client 这个名称不重要
You could name it whatever you wanted,
你可以任意命名为其他名称
but what's important to understand here is that all of
需要理解的是
our JavaScript code is now going to be accessible through the client library.
我们所有的 JavaScript 代码现在都要通过 Client 进行访问
What does that really mean?
这到底意味着什么?
How is webpack going to let us use this new client library and how does that help us?
webpack 如何使用新的 Client 库? 这又有什么帮助?
Well first off, we need to come to our index.js
首先 打开 index.js 文件
file that has both of our JavaScript files being imported.
其中导入了我们的两个 JavaScript 文件
We are going to actually export these files into the client library.
实际上 我们还要将这两个文件导出 使其进入 Client 库
Now, how it's getting into a client library
至于如何进入 Client 库
that's done by webpack and we don't have to worry about it.
这是由 webpack 完成的 我们不需要关心
But here we just need to know that all of our JavaScript is being
只需要知道所有的 JavaScript
exported from the index.js file and now it's going to be part of that client library.
都要从 index.js 文件导出 然后它们就都是 Client 库的一部分了
But how does that actually get used in our index.html?
但是这到底要如何在 index.html 中使用呢?
Well, if we come to the
打开 index.html 看一下自定义的 handleSubmit 函数
this is not going to work and it hasn't worked.
这样并不能运行 也确实没有运行成功
So now, we can add a client.handleSubmit and this is going to
现在 我们可以添加 Client.handleSubmit
reference our custom function that is now being exported into the client library.
这样就能引用到 Client 库中、刚才被导出的自定义函数了
If we make this change universally through this file and through all of our JavaScript,
如果将这个文件以及所有 JavaScript 文件都进行相应的修改
we will have fixed all of our JavaScript issues.
就能修复所有的 JavaScript 问题了
So if we go to
打开 JavaScript 文件 只需要知道你编写的所有 JavaScript 中
it now needs to reference the client library.
现在都需要引用 Client 库
So here, instead of just using the function checkForName that
所以 这里不能只使用 checkForName
would normally come to my second JavaScript function,
来调用我的第二个 JavaScript 函数
I need to make sure that I reference that checkForName through the client library.
需要确保通过 Client 库来引用 checkForName
So I've gone ahead and made that reference to client global in my code.
所以 我全局修改了自己代码中的引用情况
Now, I've restarted webpack and we can see that if I type in
现在 我重启了 webpack 可以看到当我输入
a name and hit "Submit" that our functionality gets back to working which is fantastic.
一个名字然后点击 "Submit" 后 网页功能恢复了 很神奇
Now, let's address what's going wrong with our Express server.
现在来解决 Express 服务器的问题
We have been using the webpack-dev-server in development,
我们在开发中一直使用的是 webpack-dev-server
which is an awesome tool because we don't have to
这是一个非常出色的工具 因为这样我们就不用
restart our browser every time that we make a style change.
每次一修改样式都要重启浏览器
We get to watch that update happen in live time in our browser.
可以在浏览器运行中就看到更新
But when we use this in production,
但是当我们在生产环境中时
we can't use the webpack-dev-server.
不能使用 webpack-dev-server
So we need to make sure that our Express server
我们要确保 Express 服务器
is set up correctly so that we can use it in production.
设置正确 以供生产环境使用
Now, you'll notice a really interesting thing that happens when I
现在可以看到一个有趣的现象
run the Express server that we set up at the very beginning of the course.
当我运行课程最开始设置好的 Express 服务器时
You can see that it's running on port 8080 and if I go there,
它在 8080 端口运行 如果我打开该端口
our app has gone back in time.
应用又变成了原来的样子
We are looking at the app as it was at the beginning of lesson 2.
课程第二节开始时的样子
Now, what's going on?
发生了什么?
Why does it happen that way?
为什么会出现这样的情况?
Well, we have been using the webpack-dev-server that does not rebuild our main.js.
因为我们一直在使用不会重新构建 main.js 的 webpack-dev-server
So the main.js file in the distribution folder that we're looking at right
所以现在看到的分发文件夹中的 main.js 文件
now is the same one that we built right before we added the webpack-dev-server.
与添加 webpack-dev-server 之前构建的文件相同
So we can see that there's some work that needs to be done here.
仍有一些工作需要完成
Now some of you may have noticed that in
有些同学可能已经注意到
our formHandler function we were doing a fetch request.
formHandler 函数中做了一次 fetch 请求
This is a good example of a fetch request that you could put into
这是一个很好的 fetch 请求示例 你可以将
the code of your app that could reference a local file,
其放到自己的应用中 这可以引用一个本地文件
it could also go to an external third party API and it's here as
也可以转到外部第三方 API
a reference for you so that you can make references to an API for your project.
你可以参考这段代码 为自己的项目添加 API
But right now, we're looking for a file at port 8081 called test.
现在 我们在查找 8081 端口上一个叫做 test 的文件
This points out one thing about the webpack-dev-server which
这引出了 webpack-dev-server 的一个特点
is only good for single-page apps.
其只适用于单页应用
If you need to start working with multiple pages,
如果你需要开始处理多个页面
like if we were trying to look for a test page on
比如说 如果我们想查找开发服务器
the 8080 port of the dev server, it wouldn't work.
8080 端口上的 test 页面 就不能成功
We would have to do some extra configuration or you might have
如果你想要开发服务器做到这件事
to handle your own solution if you want the dev server to do that.
我们就必须要做一些额外的设置
So this fetch request is to
这个 fetch 请求是模拟
simulate the type of fetch request you might make to another API.
你可能会对另一个 API 做出的 fetch 请求类型
But if we go look at our index.js for our server,
但是如果打开服务器的 index.js
you can see that the way we had it set up at the beginning was
可以看到一开始设置的方式
to use port 8080 which conflicts with
是使用 8080 端口 这与
our dev server that's also running on port 8080 and you
同样运行在 8080 端口的开发服务器冲突了
can't run two apps on the same port at the same time.
你不能同时在同一个端口运行两个应用
So that forces us to change this to be port 8081.
所以这迫使我们将这里修改为 8081
Now you could change it to be 3,000 or whatever you want it but 8081 is convenient.
当然也可以修改为 3000 或者其他值 不过 8081 比较方便
So now that we've set that to run on port 8081,
现在设置好 8081 端口
we can run this server at the same time as we run our webpack server.
就可以在运行 webpack 服务器的同时运行这个服务器了
So if we come over to the terminal,
打开终端
you can see that I've opened two different windows and I have
我开了两个不同的窗口
my Express side running on port 8081 and I have my webpack side running on port 8080.
Express 运行在 8081 端口 webpack 运行在 8080 端口
If we go to our app now,
现在打开我们的应用
if I put in a value and I hit "Submit",
输入一个值然后点击 "Submit"
you can see that we actually get our message being returned into the browser.
可以看到浏览器返回了消息
So that's awesome because that means that our Express server is
非常棒 这意味着我们的 Express 服务器运行正常
working and it means that all of our JavaScript is working as expected.
而且所有的 JavaScript 都按预期运行